Ali Hussain Saifuddin

Email: alisaif80@yahoo.com

Address: Flat # 8, 4th Floor, Shoaib Manzil

Soldier Bazar, Karachi Cell: +92332-3219135



Objective

My objective is to obtain a position in **Accounts & Finance Sector** that will enable me to use my strong organizational skills, work experience, educational background, and ability to work well with people. I also take special interest in updating myself with news and current affairs.

Experience Summary

Finalization of Accounts Accounts Receivable Management Bank Reconciliation Stock control Payable Management Internal Audit Controls Monthly Reporting Budgeting & Controlling

Skills Summary

Able to operate Accounting Software's Good at Spreadsheet (MS Excel) Strong Conceptual Skills Good Communication skills Team Working Multi-Tasking

Current Working Experience Re- Join M/S Penta Couriers

Position Held : Asst. Manager Finance

Organization Penta Couriers

Duration : February, 2019 – Present

Reporting to : Manager Finance & Director

Profile : Agent of China, Hong Kong, USA, Far East & Middle East Countries

Responsibilities:

- Major focus of trade debtor, follow up them for payment when invoice is due.
- Check the sale invoices after completion from operation department.
- Maintain aging schedule of customers.
- Weekly report to the director for receivable position.
- Negotiate to the bank for exchange rate when remittance received from our principle.
- Record the receipt of payment in Peach Tree Software.
 - Maintain complete Cash handling receipt & payment.



Previous Working Experience

Position Held **Chief Accountant**

Organization **Eastern Trading Corporation** Duration October 2017 - February 2019

Reporting to Managing Director

ETC are importers as well as manufacturers of all kinds of Furniture items and

Company Profile Commercial Kitchen Appliances.

Responsibilities

As an Accountant I am fully responsible for all the accounting transactions from voucher to Balance Sheet working in accounting software, my major responsibilities are:

Daily Bank Reconciliation.

Prepare weekly aging schedule of debtors.

Preparation of payments schedule as per availability of funds.

Prepare monthly payroll.

Prepare Monthly Financial Statements

Prepare monthly GST summary.

Prepare comparative statement when tender open.

Prepare special financial report as required.

Maintain proper filing records.

Provide necessary documents required in Income tax & sales tax lawyer.

Previous Working Experience

Position Held **Chief Accountant**

Organization **Penta Couriers**

Duration March, 2009 - Oct, 2017

Reporting to Managing Director

Profile Agent of China, Hong Kong, USA, Far East & Middle East Countries

Responsibilities:

Record all Accounting transaction and prepare Financial Statements in **Telly Software.**

Daily Bank Reconciliation.

Making age analysis of customers and suppliers

Maintain proper records of debtors, and follow up them on particular credit days

- Daily and monthly checking of agent's invoices
- Prepare monthly payroll
- Online submit w.h tax deduction challan
- Independently deal income tax & sales tax matters with the help of income tax lawyer.
- Provide necessary documents to income tax lawyer for submission of annual income tax return.





- Prepare special financial reports assign by the directors.
- Supervise juniors on their work, conducting timely review and solving their issues regarding area of their work
- Maintaining Fixed Asset Registers based on class of asset and recording additions & deletion of Assets.
- Maintain proper filling records.

Position Held : Accounts Executive

Organization : Kings Foods Pvt Ltd (Sister concern of Hilal Group)

Reporting to : Manager Finance

Duration : August 2007 – Feb 2009

Profile : Manufacturing sweets and candies in Pakistan.

Responsibilities

- Prepare collection receipt vouchers from all over distributors in Pakistan and then deposit the chqs into various banks as per required funds.
- Obtain daily bank position from Lahore.
- Prepare monthly W.H Tax challan and submit online
- Monthly bank reconciliation.
- Keep proper records of scrape contractors.
- Making Payroll of employees and handling other employee related matters.
- Maintaining Accounts receivables and Payable and
- their related cash inflows/outflow.
- Record weekly factory expenses.

All above work done in computer base accounting software.

Position Held : Accountant

Golden Bridge Building Material

Organization : LL.

Duration : January 2007 – June 2007

Reporting to : Owner

Importer screws and other fasteners

Company Profile : items.

Went for a special assignment

Record all the accounting transactions in an accounting software from 2004 to 2006 also prepare trial balance, financial statements, banks reconciliation, cash book and stock ledger, also advised the management for their internal controls.

Then after the management install a new accounting software where I worked to draft a proper flow chart of complete accounting cycle and checked the software properly.





Position Held : Assistant Accountant

Organization Printsol -A separate division of Mushko

Electronics (Pvt) Ltd.

Company Profile : Importer of high speed printers.

Duration : August 2006 – January 2007.

Responsibilities:

Prepare payment, receipt and journal voucher on computer base accounting software.

- Maintain stock ledger.
- Prepare payroll of 15 employees.
- Maintain proper petty cash record.
- Independently handle Income tax and Sales tax matters, with the guidance of manager finance

Position Held : Assistant Treasury

Organization : Gulistan Group of Companies

Company Profile : Manufacturer of yarn.

Duration : July 2005 – July 206

Responsibilities

- ✓ Report to Group Manager Finance.
 - Obtain daily bank balances form different banks accounts (having more than bank accounts.).
- ✓ Prepare monthly financial budget of the Group.
- ✓ Maintain daily pledge.

Professional Working Experience

M/S. Taher Moochhala and Company (Chartered Accountants), Karachi April 2000 - June 2005

Designation: as Audit Trainee and then promoted to Audit Senior

Successfully completed Five years training period from (April 25, 2000 to June 25, 2005) with M/s Moochhala Gangat & Company (Chartered Accountants). My experience consisted of diverse audit including manufacturing, insurance, software, freight forwarding, societies, trusts, constructions and service sectors. My responsibilities include:

- Reviewing, assessing and tesing of internal controls
- Supervision and review of work perform by assistants.
- Issuance of management report to the management highlighting weakness in internal controls.
- Assisting in Making and Checking of Company Financial Statements.
- Advising and helping the clients in making internal controls and book keeping of accounts.





Special Assignment during Audit period:Prepare all Vouchers, Ledgers, Trial Balance and Financial Statements of:

- M/s Texzone from 2003 to 2004
- M/s Atlas Enterprises from 2003 to 2004
- M/s Globe Link shipping from 2004 to 2005

Education	Specialization	Qualification Status
Masters of Business Administration. Hamdard University Karachi.	Accounts & Finance	Successfully Completed – 6 th Semester
Bachelors Govt Commerce College Karachi	Accounting and Commerce	Successfully Completed in 2003

Personal Profile

Nationality : Pakistani

January 06, 1980 Date of Birth

Marital Status Married